《最终幻想：灵魂深处》
(2065年12月13日 录下梦境)
Every night, the same dream, the same strange planet.
每天晚上,同样的梦境,同样奇怪的星球
But why?
但是为什么呢?
What are they trying to tell me?
它们想告诉我什么?
It's been 34 years since they arrived on this planet.
它们来到这个星球34年了
And not a day passes that the survivors...
被逼住在堡垒城市的幸存者...
forced to live in barrier cities, do not live in fear.
没有一天不是在活在恐惧中
I have vowed to end that fear.
我发誓要解除这恐惧
I believe my dreams hold the key.
我相信我的梦就是钥匙
The question is, will I be in time to save the Earth?
问题是,我来得及拯救地球吗?
(旧纽约市)
Where are you?
你在哪儿?
This is a restricted area.
这里是禁区
Do not move!
别动
What's she doing here?
她在这儿干嘛?
I don't know. We're getting her out.
不知道,我们得带她离开这
- You're coming with us.   - Behind you!
- 你得跟我们走  - 小心后面
Hold it!
站住
Damn. Let's move, people!
该死,快走吧
Two coming through the wall!
两只从墙穿过来
Hold your fire. Those tanks are flammable!
停火,那些桶子是易燃物
Ryan, Neil, let's go!
莱恩、尼尔,走吧
- What are you doing?   - There's a life form.
- 你在干什么?  - 有一个生物
- Not in years.   - There is now.
- 早就没有了  - 现在就有
Life form or not, I'm taking you in.
不管有没有,我都要带你走
Arrest me. But I'm not leaving without that life form.
逮捕我啊,没有这生物我不会离开
It's one of those days.
今天衰毙了
Captain, the transport won't wait for us much longer.
运输机是不会等我们的
I understand that.
我知道
It's in bad shape.
它的状况很糟
Tell me we're not risking our necks for this plant!
告诉我,我们不是为了这烂植物在送死
Really, it's a weed.
真的咧,是杂草
I wouldn't even call it a weed.
我看连杂草都不算
I need a minute to extract it.
等我一分钟去萃取它
That's a minute we do not have.
我们连一分钟都没有
I'm afraid he's right.
他说得没错
We have incoming.
幽怪来袭
- Captain, we need to get moving.   - Understood, sergeant.
- 队长,我们得快走  - 知道了,中士
- Could you hurry?   - Done.
- 拜托你快点  - 好了
- Captain?   - Yes, Neil?
- 队长  - 什么事,尼尔?
I'm for "let's get out of here."
我觉得咱们应该闪人
Duly noted.
知道了
Can I have this, please?
请把枪给我,谢了
- We're surrounded!   - No shit!
- 我们被包围了  - 废话
- Just relax.   - We gotta get to higher ground.
- 大伙儿别紧张  - 我们得往高处逃
Everyone, up top!
大伙儿快走,往上走
Go, go, go!
快走...快走...
- Requesting immediate evac.   - Affirmative.
- 请求立刻撤退  - 收到
Up here!
在上面
- They're right behind you!   - Come on!
- 他们就在你后面  - 快来呀
I've got you!
我抓到你了
- You okay?   - Yeah.
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
All right, everybody, here they come.
好,大伙儿,它们来了
You okay?
你没事吧?
You're gonna be all right.
你不会有事的
So, why shouldn't I arrest you?
你说我为什么不该逮捕你?
I am Dr. Aki Ross. I have clearance to be here.
我是罗安琪博士,我有到此的许可证
Not without auth...
没有授权...
I don't have time for this.
我没时间跟你争
Do you realize you risked our lives?
你明白我们在为你冒险吗?
The fact of the matter is...
事实是...
it was worth your men's lives.
这值得你跟你的弟兄冒险
Your men?
什么弟兄?
- She thinks you're a man.   - She's an idiot.
- 她以为你是男人  - 她是猪头
- I know you're not a man.   - You're an idiot.
- 我知道你不是男人  - 你也是猪头
- Funny.   - I want to talk about it.
- 好好笑  - 让我告诉你
Did it occur to you...
你有没有想过...
that we would've volunteered had we been given a choice?
我们若有选择,是否会志愿送死?
Nobody asked you to save me.
没有人叫你们救我
You have not changed a bit!
你一点也没变
Gray?
葛雷?
Yeah. Nice to see you too.
是啊,我也很高兴见到你
(42号堡垒城市 纽约市)
- Welcome back, captain.   - We're clean.
- 欢迎归队,队长  - 我们没有被感染
- Let's make sure of that.   - I hate getting scanned.
- 我们最好确定一下  - 我最讨厌接受扫描
It's probably worse for us than the Phantoms.
扫描机搞不好比幽怪更糟
These machines are suspected of causing sterility.
有人怀疑这玩意会造成不孕症
I want to have a little Neil Jr. Someday.
我想要个小尼尔
- That's a spooky thought.   - Quit busting my chops?
- 太恐怖了吧  - 你干嘛老找我碴?
Let's just do this thing.
废话少说
Yes, sir.
是,长官
- Yes, sir.   - Yes, sir.
- 是,长官  - 是,长官
Okay, next.
好了,下一个
You've gained weight.
你变胖了
It's upper-body strength. Get a girlfriend.
这叫上体位力量,交个女朋友吧
I'm working on it.
我正在努力泡美眉
My security rating allows me to bypass this.
我的保安级别让我有豁免权
Not today it doesn't.
今天可不行
Something's not right.
有点不对劲
- About this mission? Or that woman?   - Both.
- 这项任务或是那女的?  - 都是
Next.
下一个
Listen, I think...
队长,我想...
I don't care what you think.
我不管你怎么想
You're getting scanned just like everybody else.
你要跟别人一样接受扫描
Shit!
该死
They got him.
他受到感染
There must be a mistake.
一定是搞错了
You came in contact with a Phantom.
你接触到幽怪
Administering treatment shield.
启动治疗防护罩
- What level?   - Blue. Code red in 3- 1 l2 minutes.
- 什么程度感染?  - 蓝色,3分半钟后红色警戒
We have to treat him.
必须立刻替他治疗
Impossible. We'll transfer him to the treatment center.
不行,他要转到治疗中心
There's no time for that.
来不及了
Get him to the table.
把他抬上手术台
Hang in there, captain.
撑着点,队长
Locating pathogens.
搜寻病原体
Jesus, look at that thing!
天啊,你们看
How much time?
还有多少时间?
Not enough. When he reaches code red, the shield won't hold.
不多了,达到红色警戒,这个罩子就无法控制病毒
Engaging bio-etheric laser.
启动生化雷射枪
- What?   - Where'd it go?
- 怎么回事?  - 它跑哪儿了?
What is going on?
怎么了?
We've lost contact. Infestation is moving deeper.
失去踪影,病毒侵入身体
- Tracking.   - There's no time.
- 追踪  - 没时间了
- Tracking.   - You'll lose him!
- 快追踪  - 来不及了,他会死的
His treatment shield is failing.
防护罩失效了
Found it.
找到了
Come on.
快呀
It's all right.
没事了
You'll be back to normal in no time.
你很快就会恢复的
Doctor, we need to scan you for infestation.
博士,你必须接受扫描看是否有感染
That won't be necessary. I'll take responsibility.
这没有必要,我愿意负责
Hey, doc.
博士
Thanks for saving him.
谢谢你救了他
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
The military impounded my ship.
没事,军方扣留我的船
- What's with her?   - What's with her and the captain?
- 她是怎么回事?  - 她跟队长是怎么回事?
What's with her and that stupid plant?
她跟那根烂草是怎么回事?
What?
干嘛?
Forward me everything regarding the five spirits collected.
把所有搜集到的五个灵魂的资料给我
Yes, doctor.
是,博士
I thought we weren't supposed to use the "s" word.
我以为我们不该用灵魂一词
Don't get smart with me.
别跟我耍嘴皮子
Now let's see if that plant does the trick.
我们看看那根植物有没有用
(萃取植物能量波)
(比对能量波)
It's a match. We've found it.
完全符合,找到了
Yes.
太好了
The sixth spirit.
第六魂
You broke nearly every protocol.
你几乎违反了所有的规定
How long do you think this would have survived outside?
你想这根草在外面还能活多久?
There are elements in the council and military waiting to shut us down.
议会和军方有些份子等着要关闭我们
Look, 20 years ago, who discovered this energy in the Phantoms? You.
听着,谁在20年前找到幽怪的能量波?你
And who proved the same energy source existed in humans and every life form?
谁证明每种生物都有这能量?
You. You made it possible to harness that energy...
你使人能够控制这种能量...
for ovo-pacs, scanners, the barrier.
把它用在生化电池扫描机和堡垒城上
The council knows. They trust you. We're so close to proving...
议会很清楚,他们相信你,我们就快能证明...
But we still need these parts.
但我们仍所需要这些部分
Two more pieces and we've solved the puzzle!
没错,只缺两个就能解开谜底
We need to be free to find those pieces.
我们必须找到它们的能力
I want to show you something.
我给你看样东西
- What is this?   - Read.
- 这是什么?  - 读吧
"All life is born of Gaia and each life has a spirit.
所有生命来自盖雅,而每个生命都有灵魂
Each new spirit is housed in a body."
每个新灵魂都住在一个肉体内
Go on.
读下去
"Through their experiences on Earth, each spirit matures and grows.
依据他们在地球上的经验,每个灵魂不断成长
When the physical body dies...
当肉体老死后...
the mature spirit, enriched by life on Earth, returns to Gaia...
经过生命洗礼的成熟灵魂...
bringing with it the experiences...
将带着这些经验...
enabling Gaia to live and grow."
回归于盖雅,让盖雅存活并成长
It's my old diary.
我的旧日记
I wrote that 43 years ago, when I was the age you are now.
43年前我还像你这个年纪的时候写的
Dr. Sid!
席德博士
Remember Galileo? They threw him in jail because...
记得伽利略的下场吗?他被关进牢狱...
he said the Earth was not the center of the universe.
因为他说地球不是宇宙中心
That could happen to us.
这也可能发生在我们的身上
Our ideas are unpopular, Aki.
我们的主张并不受欢迎
If you have any notes that could be used against you...
如果你有对自己不利的资料...
destroy them.
快毁掉它们
- Keep them up here.   - Right.
- 记在脑子里  - 好
And stay away from the captain.
离队长远一点
He saves your life, you save his, this leads to that.
他救了你,你也救了他,别被冲昏了头
I was young once.
我也年轻过
Doctor, there is a war going on.
博士,有一场战争正在进行中
No one's young anymore.
现在再没有年轻人了
Members of the council...
各位议员...
could you please explain why?
你们能解释为什么吗?
Zeus was completed a month ago.
宙斯炮一个月前完工
If we attack the meteor, we will eliminate the Phantoms at the source.
如果用来攻击陨石,就能彻底消灭幽怪的巢穴
General Hein, calm down.
海恩将军,请冷静
We voted 6 to 2...
上次我们六比二票决定...
to postpone using the Zeus cannon to attack the Leonid Meteor.
暂缓利用宙斯炮攻击李纳陨石
We have re-convened to vote again.
这次要再投票表决
I'd like to ask the director of the Bio-Etheric Center to speak.
我想请生化能量中心主任发言
Dr. Sid, please.
席德博士
Thank you.
谢谢你
The Phantoms' nest is in the Leonid Meteor...
大家知道幽怪巢穴是...
that landed here 34 years ago.
34年前坠落地球的李纳陨石
What you see now are the records of every assault on the meteor.
这是至今每次攻击陨石的记录
Physical attacks have had utterly no effect.
猛烈攻击完全无法造成损害
This took place three months ago during a full-scale bombardment.
三个月前进行全面性轰炸行动
Please note the Phantoms outside the meteor are destroyed.
陨石外的幽怪确实被歼灭
However, inside, many that were dormant come to life...
但是潜伏在内的幽怪却复苏...
and as you see, overall Phantom density remains the same.
而你可以看到,幽怪的密度仍然跟以前一样
The newly risen aliens respond to the attack...
当复苏的幽怪遭到攻击...
by burrowing deeper into the Earth.
便钻入地球的更深层
This is very interesting to me...
这一点相当有趣...
because we see the same thing during surgery...
我们使用生化雷射...
when using bio-etheric lasers on Phantom particles, do we not?
切除幽怪病毒时也是这样,对不对?
Yes, indeed we do.
是的,没错
The injured particles escape...
受伤的病毒脱逃后...
digging themselves deeper into a patient's body.
会钻入病患更深的体内
When we increase the laser power to destroy these deeper particles...
我们为了消灭这些在更深层的病毒而加强雷射量...
we have had incidents of further injury to a patient...
我们曾意外地造成病患更大的伤害...
and in some cases...
有时候...
death.
导致死亡
What exactly does that mean?
这代表了什么?
It means there's a very good chance...
这代表一件事...
the beam from the Zeus cannon will burn the Phantoms.
宙斯炮会消灭幽怪
Exactly! Thank you.
这就对了,谢了
However, it also means that the beam energy may be too strong...
但是,那同时代表威力强大的雷射炮...
injuring the Earth.
也会伤害地球
Injure the Earth?
伤害地球?
You mean the Gaia.
你是说盖雅
- I mean...   - You mean the spirit of the Earth.
- 我是说...  - 你说的是地灵
Yes...
是的...
the spirit of the Earth.
地球的灵魂
Did he say what I think he said?
他说了我认为他说的吗?
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
I know what I'm doing. Keep your mouth shut.
我知道我在做什么,你千万别说话
This is ridiculous.
太荒谬了
With all due respect...
恕我直言...
did you come here to talk about some Gaia theory?
你是来高谈盖雅论吗?
To tell us that the planet is alive?
你说地球是活的?
That it has a spirit?
它有灵魂?
That's a fairy tale. We don't have time.
这是神话,我们没有时间
It is not a fairy tale. It is true.
这不是神话,这是真的
So if I point a gun at the Earth and fire...
如果我拿着枪朝地上开一枪...
I'm not just making a hole, I'm killing the planet.
我不只射穿一个洞还杀了地球
The Gaia theory has not been proven.
盖雅论未经证实
Even if Gaia does exist, won't we still have to remove the Phantoms?
就算盖雅存在,我们不是还是得消灭幽怪吗?
If there's a chance of success, we should take it.
如果有成功机会,就要把握
- Don't you agree?   - Of course.
- 你不同意吗?  - 当然同意
But there is an alternative to the space cannon.
但太空战炮以外有另一个选择
Another method?
有另一个方法?
A means of disabling the Phantoms.
我有一个瘫痪幽灵的方法
Please.
请说
As we know, the aliens display a distinct energy pattern.
据我们所知,这些异形散发一种能量波
It is a fact that two opposing bio-etheric waves...
只要把两道相反的生化波...
placed one over the other cancel each other out.
重叠在一起就能互相抵消
It is theoretically possible to make a wave pattern...
理论上可以重建一道能量波...
in opposition to the Phantom energy.
和幽怪的能量波完全相反
We are assembling such a wave and are near completion.
我们正在制造这种波,而且快要完成了
Members of the council...
各位议员...
gathering plants and animals...
搜集植物和动物...
to fight the Phantoms is utter nonsense.
去对抗幽怪简直是无稽之谈
The Zeus cannon is a proven, effective weapon.
宙斯炮证实是威力强大的武器
It will kill Phantoms.
它能消灭幽怪
Can we afford to wait for some crazy invention...
我们是否可以负担的起去...
some army of touchy-feely plants and animals...
等待一些毫无可以摧毁...
that offers no evidence that it will destroy the aliens?
异型证据的什么动植物兵团?
There is evidence!
当然有证据
Our partially completed energy wave...
目前半完成的能量波...
has stopped Phantom particles from spreading...
抑止幽怪病毒...
through an infected patient.
在一名受感染病患身上扩散
Do you have evidence that a terminal patient was cured?
你有证明有名垂死病患痊愈的证据?
Not cured. The wave is not complete.
不是痊愈,能量波尚未完成
We've succeeded in containing the particles safely inside the patient.
但我们成功地控制了病毒的扩散
Where is the proof?
证据在哪里?
Here.
在这里
You may have bought us some time, but at what cost?
你也许让我们有多一点时间,但是代价呢?
I can't keep hiding while you protect me.
我不能一直躲起来让你维护我
I want what life I have left to mean something.
我想在余生有所贡献
When we find the seventh and eighth spirits...
等我们找到第七和第八魂...
If we find them. What we need now is luck.
我们需要运气才可以找到它们
Luck has nothing to do with it.
这跟运气无关
Faith and hard work, girl...
你要有信心和努力...
because I'll be damned if you're going to die before me.
我绝不会让你比我先死
The council decided to postpone firing the Zeus cannon.
议会决定暂缓发射宙斯炮
I guess I put on a good show.
我想我的表现还不错
Mind if I tag along?
介意我跟来吗?
You'll probably get bored.
你会觉得无聊
So, what are you doing?
你在做什么?
Oh, I see. You're giving me the silent treatment.
我知道了,你在跟我冷战
I'm scanning the city for the seventh spirit.
我要在市内搜索第七魂
Hurry up, Neil.
尼尔,快点
- Almost got it.   - What are you doing?
- 安啦,就快好了  - 你在搞什么鬼?
We're gonna strand them for a while.
我要把他们卡在上面一阵子
Hey, it was his idea.
别看我,这是他的点子
This was your idea?
这是你的点子?
We're just helping the captain out.
我只是想帮队长的忙
Where's your sense of romance?
拜托,浪漫情调哪儿去了?
You've seen how the captain looks at her.
你看到队长看她的眼神
It's amore, baby.
那就是"爱",宝贝
What's going on?
怎么回事?
It's probably just a glitch.
卡住了吧
- Listen, Aki...   - I'm still mad at you.
- 安琪,听好...  - 我还在生你的气
- You're mad?   - Leaving your helmet on.
- 你生我的气?  - 你戴着头盔
Not telling me who you were. That doesn't seem a bit childish?
不说你是谁,未免太幼稚了
I was upset when you left for the Zeus Station without a word.
你一声不吭就跑去宙斯太空站,让我蛮生气的
- Now you know what was going on.   - Yeah.
- 现在你知道是怎么回事了吧?  - 我知道了
My operation had to be done in zero grav.
我的任务必须在无重力状态执行
Fine.
好吧
I was there on a job and you wouldn't even see me.
我去太空站出公差,而你不肯见我
I was probably collecting spirit waves.
我可能是在搜集能量波
- Now I know.   - I'm sorry!
- 我现在知道了  - 我很遗憾
Well, me too! We're both sorry.
我也是,我们都很遗憾
Will you tell me about them?
说来听听,好吗?
About what?
说什么?
About the spirits you've collected.
你搜集的灵魂
I was infected by a Phantom during an experiment.
我在一项实验中受到幽怪感染
- Normally, no one could have survived.   - How did you?
- 通常没人能活下来  - 你怎么活下来?
Dr. Sid created a membrane around the infection, keeping me alive.
席德博士用薄膜包住病原体
So the first spirit wave was me.
所以我是第一魂
The second was a fish.
第二魂是一条鱼
A fish?
鱼?
The third was a deer I found in a wildlife preserve outside Moscow.
第三魂是我在莫斯科野生保留区,找到的一只鹿
The fourth was a bird.
第四魂是一只小鸟
Ever tried to track a sparrow from outer space? It's no fun.
你试过从外太空追踪麻雀吗?一点都不好玩
- You'd love that.   - I would.
- 你一定会很喜欢的  - 你说得对
And then there was that plant I collected from Times Square.
然后就是在时代广场的那植物
- I thought that was number six.   - What?
- 那不是第六魂吗?  - 什么?
You skipped one.
你跳过一个
The fifth was a little girl dying in a hospital emergency room.
第五魂是医院急诊室,垂死的小女孩
I retrieved the sample in time, but she...
我及时采取样本,但是她...
I told her everything had a spirit: Dogs, cats, trees, little girls.
我跟她说万物都有灵魂,狗、猫、树木、小女孩
Even the Earth.
就连地球也有
I told her she wasn't dying, but returning to the Earth's spirit...
我告诉她,她不是死,只是回归到盖雅...
to Gaia.
也就是地灵
She told me that she was ready to die.
她跟我说她已准备好接受死亡
She said I didn't have to make up stories to make her feel better.
她说我不必编故事来安慰她
Only 7 years old and ready to die.
她才七岁已准备好接受死亡
I'm sorry.
很遗憾
I have work to do. I have to find the seventh and eighth spirits.
我有工作要做,我必须找到第七和第八魂
Don't, please.
别这样
You don't believe any of this, do you?
你一点都不信,是吧?
I just don't know, Aki.
我不知道
Is this why you shut me out?
所以你才避着我?
You should have told me.
你应该告诉我
I don't know how much time I have left.
我不知道我还能活多久
Who does?
谁知道呢?
I better get back to scanning.
我最好继续我的搜寻
Captain Edwards...
艾队长...
you extracted a Dr. Ross from Old New York several days ago?
几天前你在旧纽约救回罗博士?
- Yes, sir.   - What were your impressions of her?
- 是的,长官  - 你对她有什么印象?
She seemed very capable and determined, sir.
她看来非常有决心和能力
You and the Deep Eyes are being temporarily reassigned.
你的锐眼部队暂时被重新分派
You will guard Dr. Ross when she reenters the wasteland.
你们要保护罗博士回到荒原
Understood, sir.
了解
You don't understand yet, captain.
你还不了解,队长
Report any aberrant behavior in Dr. Ross to the major immediately.
她若有异常行为就向少校报告
Aberrant behavior?
异常行为?
She carries an alien infestation. We don't know what it's doing to her.
她体内有异种感染,我们不知道对她有什么影响
It might affect her judgment.
它可能影响她的判断力
They may be manipulating her.
它们也许在操控她的行为
Is the general suggesting that Dr. Ross is a spy?
将军认为罗博士是间谍?
The general is wondering why he's explaining himself to a captain.
将军在奇怪为何他要跟一个队长解释
She's had prolonged exposure to Phantom tissue.
她曾长期接触异种细胞
If this begins to manifest itself...
如果异种侵占她的身体...
she is to be placed under arrest and transported here for observation.
立刻将她拘捕,并把她带回来接受观察
It is, in fact, for her own good.
这是为了她好
Of course, sir.
当然了,长官
Major, send some of our men to keep an eye on the good captain.
少校,派手下监视队长的行动
I'm convinced these dreams are some form of communication.
我深信这些梦境是一种讯息
The message still eludes me...
虽然我不了解...
but they're coming faster now and that can only mean one thing.
但越来越频繁,这代表一件事
The Phantoms inside me are beginning to win.
我就快被体内的幽怪侵占了
Our target is 50 klicks west of Tucson.
目标在土桑市以西50公里
Phantom concentration?
幽怪密度?
Not good. We've got big metas everywhere.
情况不妙,到处都有幽怪
It's gonna be a real picnic.
这下可好玩了
Stick close. No heroics today. Everything by the book.
跟着我,千万别逞强,一切照规矩来
By the book. Right.
照规矩来,是啊
(土桑荒原)
If we drop energy buoys here, here and here...
先在这些地方放置能量浮标...
we can acquire the target and get out before they know we were there.
我们就能取得目标,趁幽怪没察觉赶快离开
The buoys attract the Phantoms?
浮标会把幽怪引来?
- Yeah.   - For a while.
- 对  - 只是一阵子
You're from the 307 th? Under General Hein?
你们是307支队的?海恩将军的部下?
Ever done wasteland recon before? It can get pretty ugly.
到荒原出过任务吗?可能会蛮可怕的
Captain, rendezvous for evac at vector 6, coordinate 279.
队长,待会撤离时到第六区,279座标会合
Roger. Stay alert for hostiles.
收到,保持警戒
Looks like they've taken the bait.
看来它们上当了
The seventh spirit should be just beyond that line of wreckage.
第七魂应该就在残骸后面
How could any living thing survive here?
这儿怎么会有生物生存下来?
We'll find out soon enough.
马上就知道了
This was the Phantom Cleansing Mission.
这原是幽怪扫荡任务
It was supposed to end the war.
本来应该让战争结束的
My father's in here somewhere.
我父亲也在这儿
All right.
好了
Let's move out, people.
我们走吧
I'll be damned.
我的天
A survivor.
一个生还者
What's it doing out here?
它在这儿干嘛?
Hoping for life to return.
希望有重返的生命
Is that our spirit, doc?
它是第七魂吗?
No.
不是
We're closing in on the life form.
我们正接近那个生物
- Distance?   - Hard to say. We're very close.
- 还有多远?  - 很难说,我们很接近了
I don't see anything.
我什么也没看到
- You're not gonna tell me it's him?   - That's impossible.
- 你不要告诉我那是他?  - 不可能
It's his ovo-pac.
不是他,是他的生化电池
How? The pacs power our weapons, the barrier cities...
不可能,电池提供能量给我们的武器、堡垒城市...
It's just bio-etheric energy.
那只是生化能量
To create that energy we use living tissue. Single-cell organisms.
我们用活体组织在制造能量,单细胞生物
- His backpack is the seventh spirit?   - Yes.
- 他的电池就是第七魂吗?  - 没错
We have incoming. Captain?
队长,幽怪来袭,收到吗?
Say again?
再说一遍?
We have incoming.
幽怪来袭
Ryan, get the soldier's pac.
莱恩,去拿那士兵的电池
I need a hand! Sarge!
我需要支援
- Those buoys? They're not working.   - Yeah.
- 那些浮标坏了  - 谢谢哦
- Are you all right?   - Of course I am.
- 你没事吧?  - 当然没事
Let's get out of here!
咱们快走吧
This shouldn't be happening.
不应该这样
Something's attracting them.
有什么把它们引来
Aki!
安琪
They're closing in fast!
它们就快追上来了
Jane, take the lead.
珍,你打前锋
Fire in the hole!
我要开火了
Get us out of here, Neil.
带我们逃出去,尼尔
- I'd love to, but...   - Just do it!
- 我也很想,但是...  - 快点
Okay, that's it.
就这样了
That doesn't look good.
她的情况不妙
We have to get her to a hospital.
我们得送她去医院
- You have your orders, sir.   - What the hell's going on?
- 你知道命令  - 这是怎么回事?
Dr. Ross is to be taken into custody now, sir.
我们必须立刻拘捕罗博士
Lower your weapons. That's an order!
把武器放下,这是命令
We relieve you of your command.
我们解除你的指挥权
You'll have to shoot me.
你得先杀了我
Stand down, captain!
队长,别反抗
Hang on, everyone!
大伙儿,抓紧了
That's enough. Hands where I can see them.
够了,把手举起来
Deep Eyes, hard to starboard!
锐眼部队,急右转
Neil, get us back to New York, fast!
尼尔,快飞回纽约
The Deep Eyes are returning, sir.
锐眼部队从荒原回来了
There was an incident.
出了一个状况
It would seem the Phantoms were attracted to Dr. Ross.
罗博士吸引了幽怪
The crew barely escaped with their lives.
他们差点回不来
Captain Edwards is still in command.
艾队长仍然有指挥权
Issue an order.
下达命令
I want Edwards and Dr. Ross placed under arrest.
我要立刻逮捕艾队长和罗博士
All research materials pertaining to Dr. Sid's wave theory...
有关席德博士能量波论的资料...
are to be confiscated.
全都给我没收
That might not go over well with the council.
议会不一定会接受
What a tragedy that would be.
那就太不幸了
This is perfect. The good captain has opened the door for us.
太完美了,队长给了我们一个好机会
The council will be at our feet...
明天他们会向我下跪...
thanking us for exposing the traitors and imploring us...
感谢我揪出叛徒...
to save them from the Phantoms.
而且从幽怪手上救出他们
How is she, doctor?
她的状况怎样?
- She is dying.   - There must be something you can do.
- 她快死了  - 你一定有办法救她
Aki is fighting with only six of the spirits.
安琪在跟六魂作战
We'll have to implant the seventh directly into her chest plate.
我必须在她胸匣植入第七魂
I think it might be damaged.
我想那胸匣受损了
We have to repair this panel quickly.
我们必须立刻修复
Her vital signs are dropping. Aki is slipping away from us.
她的生命迹象减弱,安琪撑不下去了
She needs a sympathetic spirit to help hold her in this world.
她需要一个友善的灵魂帮助挽留她
I can think of none better suited for that task than yours, captain.
最适合的人选就是你,队长
- I don't understand.   - You don't have to understand.
- 我不明白  - 你不必明白
You just be with her now.
你只要陪着她
You keep her here with us.
你挽留住她
Aki? Where are we?
安琪,我们在哪里?
On an alien planet.
异形星球
How is that possible?
怎么可能?
I'm not entirely sure.
我也不太清楚
You seem pretty calm.
你好像很冷静
I've been having this dream every night for months.
我几个月来,每晚都有同样的梦境
Dream?
梦境?
Well, whatever it is.
我也不知道是什么
You're really here, aren't you?
你真的在这儿,是吗?
What's happening to me?
我是怎么了?
Sid is implanting the seventh spirit directly into your body.
席德将第七魂直接植入你体内
Then you're my spiritual support.
那你是来精神支持我的
Gray, how sweet of you.
葛雷,你对我真好
Look, I don't think you realize how serious this situation is.
我想你不知道情况有多严重
Something you should see here, sir.
你最好过来看看
And I am watching what, major?
这是什么玩意?
It seems Dr. Ross has been recording her dreams.
罗博士录下她的梦境
And why would I be interested in...
她的梦境跟我有什么...
her dreams?
关系?
This is it. This is our evidence.
那就是了,这就是我的证据
She's under the influence of the Phantoms.
她受到幽怪的操控
The dreams should be all the council needs to authorize the Zeus cannon.
我要用来说服议会发射宙斯炮
The council is content to hide inside this barrier...
议会只顾着躲在堡垒城市...
while the world dies more every day.
让地球一天一天死去
They need a push in the right direction.
他们需要有人来推一把
Get together a group of your most trusted men.
召集你的心腹手下
Why are they staring at us?
它们为什么瞪着我们?
Not at us.
它们不是瞪着我们
Welcome back, captain.
欢迎回来
Is it over?
完了吗?
How is she, doctor?
她怎么样?
She'll be fine. But this is temporary.
她没事,但这只是暂时的
We'll need to find the eighth and final spirit to cure her.
一定要找到最后的第八魂才能救她
Aki, can you hear me?
安琪,你听到吗?
I finished it.
我做完梦了
I know what it means.
我知道它的意思
I know what the Phantoms really are.
我知道幽怪到底是什么
Nobody move! You're all under arrest!
别动!你们被捕了
We have them, sir.
我逮住他们了
Sir?
长官?
My wife and daughter...
我太太和女儿...
were killed by Phantoms in the San Francisco Barrier City.
在旧金山堡垒城市被幽怪害死
Did I ever tell you that?
我有没有提过?
I try to imagine what that must have been like...
我试着想像她们的感受...
seeing everyone around you fall over dead for no apparent reason.
看着身边的人无缘无故死去
And then, at the end, feeling something next to you...
最后感觉有什么在你身边...
invisible...
无形的...
touching you...
触碰你...
reaching inside your body...
伸入你的躯体内...
You've lost family, haven't you?
你也失去了家人,对吧?
Yes, sir.
是的
That's why I trust you.
所以我才信任你
All of you.
你们每个人
You know what must be done.
你们知道该怎么做
(堡垒主控中心)
Security override.
解除安全密码
Perimeter breach.
围场被破
Major, arrest these men.
少校,逮捕他们
- Take it easy.   - Stand up. Go.
- 别乱来  - 起来,走
You are relieved of your post. Don't ask questions.
你们被解职了,别多问
Reduce power to Sector 31.
降低31段的防护能源
You realize that the Phantoms...
你知道幽怪...
What I realize...
据我所知...
is we must force the council to take action.
我们要逼迫议会消灭敌人
25% of energy pipe alpha redirected.
第一个电管二成五的能量改向
Lowering power output to Sector 31.
降低31段防护能力
Barrier breach in Sector 31. They're coming through now.
31段防护罩失效,幽怪进来了
We can handle a few Phantoms in a contained space.
我们可以在密封的空间杀死几只幽怪
Relax, major. When this night's over, you're going to be a hero.
别紧张,少校,明天一早你就成为英雄
- I don't...   - But you saw it.
- 我不...  - 你也看到了
I'm not sure what I saw. How can you be?
我不确定我看到的,你怎么能确定?
Captain, please, let her continue.
队长,请你让她说下去
Why do you think we've never been able to determine...
我们为什么一直没办法确定...
a relationship between the human-sized Phantoms and the giant ones?
人形大小的幽怪跟庞大幽怪的关系?
Excuse me, doc, but what frigging relationship?
拜托,它们有什么鬼关系?
You got your human-sized Phantoms, creepy caterpillary Phantoms...
有人形幽怪、恶心的毛虫幽怪...
flying Phantoms and my favorite...
会飞的幽怪...
the big, fat, giant Phantoms.
还有巨大肥胖的幽怪
Down, boy.
冷静点
If you've spent time in the field...
要是你常跟它们周旋...
you know there is no relationship. It's like a zoo out there.
就知道它们没有关系,那外面是一团乱
I think the giant ones are like our whales or elephants.
没错,大幽怪就像我们的鲸鱼或大象
But why would an invading army bring whales and elephants along?
但是侵略部队带鲸鱼大象来干嘛?
Unless their ship was a crazy Noah's Ark?
除非那是外星人的诺亚方舟?
We have always assumed that the meteor...
我们一直以为陨石...
was intended as a form of transportation. Perhaps not.
是交通工具,也许它不是
The meteor is a chunk of their planet that got thrown into space...
陨石只是一块他们炸毁星球后...
when they destroyed their world.
被扔到太空中的碎片
But how could they survive the trip across outer space?
它们怎么能活着通过太空?
They didn't.
它们没存活
This makes a creepy kind of sense.
这好像有点恐怖的道理
What do you think?
你觉得呢?
I think that explains why we never had a chance.
所以我们根本就赢不了它们
All our strategies are based on one assumption:
我们的战略都根据一种假设:
That we were fighting alien invaders.
敌人是异形侵略者
Think of the dream, Gray. How they died.
你想想梦中它们是怎么死的
Since then, all they've known is suffering.
自从那时候之后,它们只认识痛苦
They're not an invading army.
它们不是侵略兵团
They're ghosts.
它们是鬼魂
How many Phantoms?
有多少幽怪?
More than enough to convince the council.
多到一定可以说服议会的
Excellent. Sound an alert. Send a squad out to eliminate them.
太好了,示警,立刻派部队去消灭它们
Alert status. Full deployment.
全面警戒、全体动员
I have numerous Phantom contacts!
有很多幽怪来袭
Of course you do.
当然了
Outside of Sector 31 and moving at incredible speed.
在31段以外,而且行动迅速
What the hell is going on?
这是怎么回事?
They're in the pipes.
它们在管道中
They're moving with the bio-etheric energy flow.
跟着生化电力一起流窜
That's impossible. Nothing could survive in those pipes.
不可能,没有东西可以在这些管子中存活下来
We've got a big one heading this way. Meta class, sir.
一只巨大幽怪正朝这儿冲来,是米达种的,队长
Oh, my God.
我的天
Hold your fire!
别开枪
What have I done?
我做了什么?
Come on, Neil. We need a way out. You're our man. Think.
尼尔,我们得逃出去,你是高手,快想办法
These walls are titanium alloy and the bars are pulse-sonic lasers.
这是钛合金钢柱和雷射光束
It's not like I can just wave a magic wand and...
我不能就这样施展魔法...
- Neil, I'm impressed.   - That makes two of us.
- 我很佩服你  - 我也很佩服自己
Proceed to the nearest evacuation facility.
立刻前往最近的撤退区
We should proceed to the nearest evacuation facility.
我们应该立刻最近的撤退区
- Here they come.   - But the others! Dr. Sid!
- 它们来了  - 别人呢?席德博士!
Deep Eyes'll take care of him.
锐眼部队会保护他
Why can we see them now?
我们怎么会看得见它们?
They must be carrying a residual charge from the barrier.
它们身上残留防护罩的电力
Behind you!
小心后面
All aboard, captain!
全都上车了
We need to find my ship.
我们需要找我的太空船
If it was towed here, it would be in the military hangar.
它一定是被拖到军事停机棚
That's a big "if."
搞不好不是
Look out!
小心!
Get us onto the platform.
快开到月台
Okay, now what?
现在呢?
We're going through the station.
我们要穿越车站
With all due respect...
恕我直言...
- Excuse me, captain.   - The station.
- 对不起,队长  - 车站
We're going through it.
我们要冲过去
It's the only way.
那是唯一的出路
So I gather this will be somewhat of a rough ride?
我猜这会是一个巅簸之旅?
You've got a talent for understatement.
博士,你真会说冷笑话
Hang on, everybody!
坐好了
Doc?
博士?
Interesting.
有意思
- Anybody hurt?   - Captain.
- 有人受伤吗?  - 队长
Oh, God. Talk to me, sarge.
老天,快说话,中士
Ouch!
好痛
- Give me a hand.   - Right.
- 帮我个忙  - 好
We're risking further injury. We need the proper tools.
他会加重伤势的,我们需要适合的工具
They're in my ship.
工具在我船上
- No. No, doc. No drugs.   - Captain?
- 不,我不要打针下药  - 队长?
You heard the man.
你听他的
We'll be back.
我们会回来的
- I'll stay with him.   - Me too.
- 我留下来陪他  - 我也是
Nobody's staying.
谁都别留下来
- Just give me a gun.   - You got it.
- 给我一把枪  - 没问题
Give him a weapon. Do it!
把枪给他,快点
We'll be back for you.
我会回来救你
You hear me?
听到吗?
I hear you, captain. Now, get out of here.
听到了,队长,快走吧
Let's move out.
走吧
A quad-axle ATV. This is good.
四轴越野车,棒呆了
It can be used to retrieve Ryan and bring him here.
我们可以去把莱恩救回来
We'll need to replace these spent fuel cells.
但是要换电池
There could be some live ovo-pacs in the hangar.
停机棚一定有新的电池
Check the hangar. Neil, get us ready for takeoff.
你去停机棚,尼尔,去启动引擎
Aki and Dr. Sid, prep the Quatro.
安琪和席德博士,启动越野车
I'll go rotate the airtray.
我去塔台开启平台
This city may be lost, but we are not. Let's do this and get out.
城市也许沦陷了,但我们不会,我们一定会逃出去
Be careful.
小心点
You too.
你也是
Oh, yeah.
好耶
Neil, do you read me?
尼尔,收到吗?
Loud and clear, captain.
收到了,队长
This baby'll fly itself.
这玩意是全自动的
Flight path is set.
航道设定好了
Beginning rotation.
转动平台
Stop the airtray. We have a problem.
停下来,有问题
An impound tractor is attached to the ship.
太空船连着一辆被拖吊的牵引车
Can you disengage from the cockpit?
你能从驾驶舱解开它吗?
Permission to go outside and detach the coupling.
请让我到外面解开它
Do it.
快去
There's the problem.
问题在那
The controls are locked, naturally.
控制板被锁住了
You think we'll get out of here alive?
咱们逃得出去吗?
I wonder if anybody else has gotten out.
不知道以前有没有人逃出去
You think anyone's made it this far?
你觉得有人逃了这么远吗?
Will this eighth-spirit stuff work against the Phantoms?
第八魂这玩意能消灭幽怪吗?
What if it's all mumbo-jumbo?
也许全都是胡扯蛋?
Can we stop talking? I'm trying to concentrate here.
拜托你别唠叨了吧?让我专心吧
What's happening down there?
下面发生什么事?
Nothing we can't handle.
我们搞得定啦
- Neil, what's your status?   - Almost there.
- 尼尔,怎么样?  - 快好了
Get back inside.
你们快回去
We're fine. Jane is negotiating with extreme prejudice.
放心,珍在展开强硬政策
Talk to me, Jane.
珍,快回答
No problem here, captain.
我没问题
Yes! Captain, we are good to go.
好了,可以出发了
Jane, get out of there.
珍,快走
Get out of there now! Go! Jane!
珍,快走呀,赶快走
Get the hell out of there!
快点离开那儿
The shield is powered and ready.
防护罩启动了
- Where are you going?   - To the cockpit.
- 你要去哪儿?  - 去驾驶舱
We're in countdown to liftoff.
我们要倒数发射
No, wait. It's too dangerous. Aki!
等一下,太危险了,别去
Over here, you son of a bitch!
我在这儿,臭怪物
Gray, do you read me? What's happening?
你收到吗?怎么回事?
You and Sid are getting out of here now.
你和席德快走
- No! We can't just leave everyone.   - Everyone's dead!
- 不,我不能丢下大伙儿  - 大伙儿都死了
- I'm not leaving without you.   - Sorry, but you don't have a choice.
- 我不能丢下你  - 抱歉,你别无选择
Goodbye, Aki.
再见,安琪
Gray, come on!
葛雷,快上来
I just...
我很想...
I wish I could believe they were in a better place.
我很想相信他们到更好的地方
(宙斯太空站)
(确认目的地 获准前进)
I enlarged the scanning perimeter...
我扩大搜索范围...
to include an area that we had previously overlooked.
包括一个之前没找过的地方
The impact crater.
陨石坑
Strange place to find the eighth spirit.
好个奇怪的第八魂藏身处
Yes, really quite astonishing.
很不可思议
But nothing could survive in there except Phantoms.
那儿除了幽怪没别的生物可以存活下来
Precisely.
没错
Which suggests that the eighth spirit is a Phantom spirit.
也就是说第八魂是幽怪
I can't explain it at the moment, but once we get down there...
我目前不能解释,只要你下去...
- you will understand...   - Wait, doctor. That's a one-way trip.
- 就会明白的...  - 慢着,这是一去不回
Yes, I expected that's how you would evaluate our chances.
是的,我就知道你是这么评估我们的机会的
Well, am I wrong?
我说错了吗?
No, I agree. We probably...
没错,我同意,我们也许...
won't live long enough to extract the eighth spirit from the crater.
无法活着把第八魂萃取回来
Then why even try it?
那为什么还要去试?
Because we don't need to extract the eighth spirit.
因为我们不必把第八魂萃取回来
If we can't bring the final spirit here...
如果我们无法找到最后一魂...
we can go there and complete the wave inside the crater.
就直接在陨石坑完成能量波
Yes, exactly.
一点也没错
And how do we do that, exactly?
我们该怎么做?
I can construct a device that...
我会设计一个装置...
would attach to Aki's chest plate to gather the eighth spirit and...
装在安琪身上让她采集第八魂...
And what?
然后呢?
And then we wait and see what happens.
然后就等着瞧
That's it?
就这样?
That's your plan? We wait and see what happens?
你的计划就是等着瞧?
Oh, good. Well, I got my own plan.
太好了,我也有计划
We keep scanning the surface from orbit...
继续从轨道扫描地球表面...
and maybe we'll find a compatible spirit somewhere else.
也许能在别处找到相容的第八魂
I say we go in.
我建议下去
What caused the barrier to fail, General Hein?
海恩将军,请问防护罩为什么会失灵?
I'm afraid it was only a matter of time...
幽怪对防护罩产生抵抗力...
before the Phantoms developed an immunity to our barriers.
这是迟早会发生的事
But I am relieved to see that you and the council...
但是我很高兴看到你和议员们...
were able to evacuate to Houston without incident.
都安全地撤逃到休士顿
It was a terrible loss suffered this evening.
今晚的事件是一场悲剧
The council has reconsidered your proposal to fire the Zeus cannon.
议会重新考量了你对发射宙斯炮的提议
I see.
很好
We are transmitting the access codes to you now.
我们现在就把发射密码传给你
And, general...
将军...
best of luck to us all.
祝大家好运
Prepare to fire the cannon.
准备发射宙斯炮
The target, sir?
目标是?
The Phantom crater.
幽怪陨石坑
(里海山脉 幽怪陨石坑)
Preparing to drop in three, two, one.
准备降落,3、2、1
Powering the shield.
启动防护罩
Okay, we're over the meteor.
我们在陨石坑上方
Do you have it in sight, doctor?
你看到了吗?
There are so many of them.
有太多幽怪了
Wait.
等等
Yes! I'm tracking the eighth spirit along the crater's surface.
是的,我追踪在陨石坑表面的第八魂
All right. Now let's take a closer look.
好,那就靠近一点
Ready to fire in three minutes.
三分钟后发射
Ovo-pacs at maximum. Transferring plasma flow to auto.
开到最强电力,转换自动流量
Counter-thrusters are engaged.
反制推动器准备好了
Lox flow de-coupled. Status is green.
开启流管锁,一切正常
We have something on radar over the impact site, sir.
我们发现陨石坑有动静
It's her.
是她
Sir?
长官?
Just a traitor under the influence of the enemy.
是被敌人控制的叛徒
Continue the countdown.
继续倒数计时
We'll take them all out at the same time.
我们一起把它们消灭掉
We're closing on the Phantom. Contact in 30 seconds.
接近幽怪了,三十秒后接触
Target locked.
目标锁定
Ready to fire on your command.
等待你下令发射
It's a match! It's a perfect match!
完全符合,能量波完全符合
- Scanners ready.   - Fire.
- 准备好了  - 发射
What was that?
那是什么?
It's the Zeus. They're firing on the crater.
是宙斯炮,他们向陨石坑发射宙斯炮
- Are you all right?   - A little shaken. Stand by.
- 你们没事吧?  - 我们吓了一跳,请待命
Sid, the eighth spirit is not on our scanner. Do you have it?
我在扫描器上看不到第八魂,你看到吗?
The eighth spirit...
第八魂...
has been destroyed.
被消灭了
What will we do now?
现在该怎么办?
Nothing. This mission is over.
不怎么办,任务结束
- Let's get out of here.   - Incoming!
- 快走吧  - 幽怪来袭
What is that?
是什么?
If you're getting us out, you better do it now.
我们要走就得趁现在
Hold on!
扣紧我们
I can't hold on to you.
我扣不住你们了
Unable to maintain altitude.
无法维持高度
Emergency landing procedures.
启动紧急降落程序
Come in. Come in, please.
快回答我
Aki, Gray, can you hear me?
你们收到吗?
I need to talk to the station. Can you patch us through?
博士,你能帮我接太空站吗?
- What is that thing?   - I don't know, sir.
- 什么鬼玩意?  - 我不知道
Incoming message, sir.
讯息传送进来
General Hein, cease fire immediately.
海恩将军,请你立刻停火
What you're seeing is the living spirit of an alien's home world.
你所看到的是外星人的地灵
Their planet was destroyed and landed here.
它们的星球被毁灭后降落到地球
This is not an invasion. It never was.
这从一开始就不是侵略行动
I see. What have we been fighting all this time? Ghosts?
原来如此,那我们都在跟什么打仗?异形鬼吗?
Yes.
没错
Spirits that are confused, lost and angry.
感到迷惑、失落和愤怒的鬼魂
Right. And these spirits are coming out of this Gaia thing.
对,这些鬼都来自盖雅
You have to listen.
你要听我说
Alien Gaia, Earth Gaia. Even if I believed that...
异形盖雅、地球盖雅,就算我信这套...
the Earth's under attack from an aggressor...
地球仍然受到必须被不择手段...
who must be destroyed at all costs.
消灭掉的侵略者的攻击
The cost may be the entire planet, sir.
代价是地球也会被毁灭
Firing on the alien Gaia will only make it stronger.
异形盖雅遭到攻击会更强大
Since you're under the alien's influence, I'll take it that we're...
既然你是受到外星人的控制,我觉得...
taking the correct action.
我们做对了
So take your last few moments and prepare to meet your Gaia.
你就等着去见你的盖雅吧
Continue to fire until the invader has been destroyed.
继续开火,直到完全歼灭侵略者
General, the system's overheating.
将军,系统过热了
We'll hit again and keep on hitting it until it's dead.
我要不断攻击直到它们全死光
But we're not even sure if it's having any effect.
我们不晓得有没有效
No effect? We've got them on the run, soldier.
有没有效?它们走投无路了
This is our moment of victory. I order you to fire.
胜利就快来临,我命令你发射
- The system won't allow us to fire.   - We'll see about that.
- 系统无法继续发射  - 等着瞧吧
Our shield is out. We're sitting ducks. Come on!
防护罩失效,这是等死,来吧
This is not a good place to be.
这不是个可以留下的好地方
What the hell is that? Is it what I think it is?
什么东东?那是我以为的东东吗?
Yes, it's Gaia.
是,这就是盖雅
This is definitely not a good place to be.
这的确不是个可以留下的好地方
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
I'm fine. I have to talk to Dr. Sid.
没事,我得跟希德博士通话
Sid, do you read me?
希德,你收到吗?
Go ahead, I'm still here.
我还在,说吧
We're looking at Gaia. Do you hear me, Sid? Gaia.
盖雅就在我们眼前,听到吗?盖雅
This explains why the eighth spirit appeared here.
这解释了为什么第八魂会在这里
Yes.
没错
Yes, that's it!
没错,这就对了
A Phantom changed into the eighth spirit...
一只幽怪接触到我们盖雅产生的生命...
at touching a life born from our own Gaia.
于是它转变成第八魂
It would've gotten a different energy signature...
所以它的能量波...
that set it apart from the other Phantoms.
才会跟别的幽怪不同
You couldn't have hoped for a better location...
这是找到新而相容的第八魂...
to find a new compatible spirit.
的最佳地点
Whatever you do, don't move. Stay right where you are.
无论如何都不要动,留在原地
Staying where we are isn't as easy as it sounds.
留在这里可不是件容易的事
Don't shoot any of them!
别对它们任何一个开枪
You could very well destroy our last hope.
你很可能会毁掉最后一线希望
What do you suggest? Ask them to play nice?
我该怎样?叫它们乖一点吗?
Combat strategy is your area of expertise, captain, not mine.
战略是你的专长,队长,不是我的
I have a reading in the fissure. See it?
你说我收到能量波,你看到吗?
Yes! A compatible spirit. It must be very near you.
是的,那是相容的第八魂,它一定很接近你
Well? Which one is it?
那么,哪一个才是?
Which one?
哪一个?
It's difficult to narrow down. Just a moment, please.
我看不出来,请等一下
It's getting crowded in here. Aki, we don't have time.
这里变得太挤了,没有时间了
With the hope of new life...
抱着新生命的希望...
has Gaia changed the Phantom within?
盖雅是否改变了内在的幽怪吗?
I have it.
我找到了
Gray, get in here. I need you!
快进来,我需要你
Hear me, Sid? The wave pattern is complete.
你收到吗?能量波完成了
Yes, I read you. This is wonderful.
收到了,真是太好了
I don't see how you found the final spirit.
我不知道你怎样找到最后一魂
It found me, doctor.
它找到我
Oh, my word.
我的天
I see now. I understand.
我知道了,我懂了
I don't understand! What's going on?
我不懂,到底是怎么回事?
The ovo-pac will project the wave.
电池发射能量波
- But we'll be defenseless.   - Just do it!
- 我们会变得手无寸铁  - 快点
I hope you know what you're doing.
我希望你们知道在干嘛
We'll use it to project the wave.
我们要用防护罩发射能量波
Dr. Sid was right. I have it. The eighth spirit.
博士说得对,我得到第八魂
I'm cured, Gray.
我痊愈了
- Are you sure you have it?   - Yes, I'm sure.
- 你确定你得到最后的一魂?  - 我很确定
- How can you know?   - Don't worry. A Phantom told me.
- 你怎么知道?  - 别担心,一只幽怪告诉我的
Oh, great.
棒呆了
That's it. Shield on.
好了,启动防护罩
It's not working. We have to do something.
没有用,赶快想办法
If this doesn't work, then it's already too late.
这没用的话一切都太迟了
Trust me.
相信我
I'll blast you all to hell.
我要把你们打下地狱
Oh, no. No!
不...
Get down!
趴下来
- Warning. System overload.   - I know.
- 警告,系统超载  - 我知道
- Warning. System overload.   - I know!
- 警告,系统超载  - 我知道了
But it must be done.
但一定要这样
Fire.
发射,快呀
Fire, damn you!
Fire!
发射
Don't leave me, Gray.
别丢下我
Told Sid this was a one-way trip.
我告诉博士这是一去不回
Looks like I was right.
看来我说对了
No, Gray. Hang on, please.
不,你要撑下去
I still have the wave.
我仍有能量波
We can get through this.
我们撑的过去的
- We won't make it.   - We will make it.
- 来不及了  - 来得及
We both know that isn't true.
我们都知道来不及了
Help me.
扶我起来
Listen to me.
听我说
You saved my life once. Now I want you to save yourself.
你救过我,我要你救自己
Gray, no. Please?
不,求求你?
Let me do this, Aki. Trust me.
让我这么做,相信我
Don't leave me, Gray.
葛雷,别离开我
You've been saying that death isn't the end.
你一直说死亡并不是终结
Don't back out on me now that I finally believe.
在我终于相信后,别说不是
I love you.
我爱你
Oh, it's warm.
哦,好暖啊